RG 069:019, James Bradford Olcott Papers
Connecticut State Library
- Series 5. Photographs, 1878-1937, undated
  - Garden Tools
    - Cart drawn by a horse, undated; 2 photographs, b&w, 4.25 x 6.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Interior of shed with assorment of tools, undated; b&w, 6.75 x 5 in. (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Garden tools hanging in the shed, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 70)
      Inscription on photograph: His golf-clubs.
    - Assortment of garden tools hanging in the shed, undated; b&w, 6.75 x 4.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Olcott sitting in the shed and writing surrounded by garden tools, undated; b&w, 6.75 x 5 in. (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Olcott standing with assortment of garden tools, the turf garden behind him, undated; 3 copies, b&w, 5 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - Assortment of garden tools propped up against bushes, "Under the big pine - working headquarters; undated; double-sided, b&w, 7.75 x 5.25 in. (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Various styles of carts with descriptions, 1878 April 6; 6 clippings, b&w, (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Mr. Olcott's handy weeding set, undated; 11 copies, print, text with illustration, b&w, 10 x 8 in. (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Assortment of garden tools hanging in shed, undated; 2 copies, b&w, 6.75 x 4.75 in., mounted on cardboard 10 x 8 in. (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - The Ranch
    Residence of James Bradford Olcott in Manchester, Conn.
    - The well, undated; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 88)
      The first thing built at the ranch prior to the building of the house.
    - Living room, 1937; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 89)
      West end with bookcase and stairs leading to the study.
    - Living room, 1937; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 90)
      East end with woman sitting in front of firelplace.
    - Study, 1936; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 91)
      Showing fireplace and the corner of Olcott's desck to the right.
    - Exterior of the Ranch, 1936; b&w, 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 12, Folder 92)
      Showing the well in front of the building and a road running beside to the left.
    - Exterior of the Ranch, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6 in. (Box 12, Folder 95)
      Showing the well in front of the building and an automobile parked next to the well.
    - Exterior of the Ranch, undated; b&w, 5.75 x 8 in. (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - General Photographs
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated; 2 leaves (4 photographs), b&w, 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 96)
      Side one: Painting of a woman herding sheep.
      Side two: Grass experimentation boxes.
      Turf garden with a number of sample squares. Three men and three women stand at the far end of the garden.
      Map with report on grass acquisition in England and France.
      Photos are of various sizes and mounted on paper.
    - Toy figures of seveal animals, mainly sheep in a cage., undated; b&w, 3 x 5 in., mounted on cardboard (Box 12, Folder 97)
      Inscription on photo: The art of grazing "in a nutshell".
    - A woman standing at the end of a long wooded path, undated; b&w, 7.5 x 4.75 in. (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - Page of Olcott's notes, undated; b&w, 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Several plants on a windowsill, undated; b&w, 3.5 x 4.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Street beautiful on the American plan, undated; 34 copies, b&w, 6 x 9 in. (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Road construction, undated; pen & ink, b&w, 5.5 x 7.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 104)
- Series 6. Newspaper clippings, 1881-1938, undated
  - General newsclippings, 1881-1938, undated (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Obituaries, 1910-1927 (Box 4, Folder 12)